A Guide to the Potter Interstate 66 Materials, 1958-1998
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Potter Interstate 66 Materials, 1958-1998
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
RG 380
1 box.
Potter, Laurence E., 1916-1998
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Bob Connelly, neighbor of Laurence Potter, in August 2001.
Scope and Content
RG 380 contains material created and collected by Laurence Potter. Potter (1916-1998) lived at 1904 N. Johnson Street. The collection measures .21 linear feet and covers the years 1958-1998; materials in this collection are scattered throughout this time period. Potter, worried that his home was in the path of the future Interstate 66 (I-66), started sending letters to staff within Arlington County and to the Virginia Department of Highways (VDH), expressing concern for his home and dissatisfaction with the way the VDH was handling the development of the project.
There are also research materials Potter collected over time, including 78 photographs (color and black and white) of I-66 construction around his home, I-66 planning and right-of-way documentation, newspaper articles, and an analysis of a television show about highway construction.
Arrangement
RG 380 has only one series with ten files. Files were created by type of document or subject matter.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Other collections dealing with the construction of I-66 are RG 43, Interstate 66, and RG 379, Arlington Coalition on Transportation Records.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Interstate 66 (Va. and Washington, D.C.); Arlington (Va.); Arlington County (Va.)
Contents List
- Series 1 (Box 1)
  - Analysis of Potmac I-266 River Crossing, 1964
  - Bumper Stickers
  - Cherrydale Citizens Association Membership Directory, 1983-1984
  - Correspondence, 1962-1964
  - Newspaper Articles, 1962-1967, 1974, 1995, 1998, n.d.
  - Photographs
  - Public Law Booklet, 1959-1961
  - Right-of-Way Costs
  - Report: Alternate Locations for I-66 by Arlington County Office of Planning and Department of Public Service, 1958
  - Television Program, "The Great Highway Robbery," with David Brinkley, October 1, 1962